Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Medical Men and Management on doctors and how they use management in hospitals and surgery. This contains material on Dr. Ernest Coddman who was very interested in the end result system of surgery and Dr. Dickenson who worked with him as well as som (Box 28)
  - J. Curtis Ball Letter (9/26/79) on Jau Don Ball, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Letter to J. Curtis Ball (On Jau Don Ball) 10/11/79, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Jau Don Ball Data from California and Western Medicine on Ball's Death Nov. 1936, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Ernestine Black - Wife of Jau Don Ball 1980, 1926-1980 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Jau Don Ball Letters - And Herman Adler, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Jau Don Ball Letters to August Vollmer 1915-1926 - Jau Don Ball (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Jau Don Ball Letters on Psychiatry and Industry 1919, 1918-1919 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Jau Don Ball Letters, 1929-1979 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Jau Don Ball Chart of Vocations 1919 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Jau Don Ball "The Correlation of Neurology, Psychiatry, Psychology, and General Medicine on Scientific AIDs to Industrial Efficiency" Amer. Jl. Of Insanity, April 1919, Vol. 75, pp. 521-555 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Jau Don Ball, "Industrial Psychiatry" April 1922 - Ball 1922 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Article on Jau Don Ball "Send For The Doctor" Sunset Magazine, August 1926, pp.28-29, 54-56 - J.D. Ball, 1926-1981 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Morris S. Viteles, "Psychology and Psychiatry in Industry" 1928 in Mental Hygiene (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Industrial Psychiatry Articles Survey, 1915-1922, 10/2/85 - File Under Dr. Ball, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Data on Dr. Jau Don Ball, 1917-1988 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Jau Don Ball and Robert, Jau Don Ball Data, 1916-1921 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Susan Boone - Smith College, Jarrett-Southard 1978 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Mary Jarrett Paper, Folders 1 and 5, 1918-1922 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    Copies and original documents in two red folders
  - Mary Jarrett Papers, Folders 6 and 10, 1919-1926 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    Original documents and copies in two red folders
  - Mary Jarrett Papers, Folders 5 and 6, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    Originals and copies of documents in three red folders
  - Van Kleeck Papers (Social Welfare History Archives Center), 1983 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Photo of Mary Jarrett (Ernest Codman Associate) in Office 1918 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    Envelope with original photo
  - Byrom Letters 1979 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Outline of Southard Book on Mental Hygiene in Industry 1919 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Ernest Codman "End Result Chart" 1915, 1912-1915 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Roger Alan Crabbs Letters 1979, 1915-1979 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Preface to Ernest Codman's Book: The Shoulder - On His Life, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Data on Efficient Mgt. of Hospitals: 1913-1922 and Ernest Codman Letters (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - Codman Material, 1915-1980 (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - Data on Ernest Codman from Countway Medical Library 1978, 1915-1978 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Codman Letters, 1913-1915 (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - Ernest Codman Paper 1979 (Raw Data - Letters and Reports), 1915-1979 (Box 28, Folder 45)
  - Ernest Codman Data - Articles and Letters - Reports (From Richard Wolfe 1978), 1912-1978 (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Data on Management and Hospitals - Gilbreth, Codman, etc. (On End Result System 1980) - Medical Men and Mgt. (Box 28, Folder 47)
  - Data on Codman Surgical Instruments, Randolph, Mass., 800-225-0460, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 48)
  - Liz Lunbeck on Dr. Codman 6/25/82, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 49)
  - Vida Grayson Letters on Dr. Southard - 1979 Medical Men and Mgt, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence with Susan Reverby on Ernest Codman and "End Result System" of Hospital Efficiency - 1979 Codman, 1979- 1980 (Box 28, Folder 51)
  - Note from Susan Reverby on Codman Papers 1983 (Box 28, Folder 52)
  - Jo A. Dvorak - Paper, Hospital Standards Study, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence with H. Martin Deranian on Dentists and Mgt., 1980 (Box 28, Folder 54)
  - Psychiatry and Industry 1915-1932 11/2/85, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 55)
- Robert Valentine Data, was found in his daughters house in MA. Robert Valentines daughter made copies of everything she has. It also includes Mary Van Kleek data and the International Industrial Relations Association (1929) of which Kleek was involv (Box 29)
  - Typed Versions of 1991 Paper on Robert Valentine (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Research Project on Robert Valentine 1991 - Outlining What Racquel Frederiks Did in 1990 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Robert Valentine Paper Made by Racquel A. Frederiks, March 29-30, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Meeting on R. Valentine - Jan. 7, 1917 - and Charles S. Bird, Charlotte Taylor (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Data on Robert Valentine from Harvard Univ. Student Files 1991 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Robert Valentine Data, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Robert Valentine Marriage, Death Data - Death Certificate # 32156 - NYC, Nov. 14, 1916, 1916-1964 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Valentine Paper in Proceedings Southwest Academy of Mgt. 1992 - File Under Valentine, 1991-1992 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Robert G. Valentine "What The Awakened Employer is Thinking on Employment" American Labor Legislation Review, June 1915, Vol. V. #21, pp. 423-428 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Robert Valentine Data - 1964 Research, Includes Death Certificate (now in his death and obituary file) (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Mrs. Charlotte Taylor Correspondence (Valentine's Daughter) 1990-1991, 1915-1991 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Robert Valentine and Street Railway Strike of NY City July 22-August 9, 1916, From Charlotte Taylor (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Robert Valentine Data (Copies of Personal Papers - Booklets) From Charlotte Taylor 1990 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Robert Valentine and Garment Workers 1916, 1916-1991 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Robert Valentine and Ladies Garment Workers from Gloria Frock 1991, 1916-1991 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Articles Written by Robert G. Valentine From Charlotte Taylor 1990 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Job Analysis Form by Valentine and Gregg NY City 1918, From R. Strassberg 2/18/91 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Robert Valentine Report 1915 (Textile Industry) (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Robert Valentine Letter 12/19/12 (From His Daughter) (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Robert Valentine Papers, 1901-1913 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    Copies of original documents and photos
  - Robert Valentine Letter 1912 (Copies from His Daughter Mrs. Taylor) (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Robert Valentine and NY Street Railway Strike - 1916, 1916-1991 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Robert Valentine in The New Republic Nov. 25, 1916, pp. 84-85 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Dr. Herman Adler (with Valentine when he died 11/04/1916) (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - R. Valentine's Associates - Robert P. Boss 1990, 1990-1991 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Emory Buckner (was with R. Valentine 11-14-1916), 1941-1968 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Industrial Relations in WWI and Felix Frankfurter and Robert Valentine (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Felix Frankfurter and R. Valentine - Brandeis and Valentine, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Felix Frankfurter and Valentine, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Copy of Robert Valentine Report from Charlotte Taylor (His Daughter) 1991 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Winfred Thaxter Denison Deed Nov. 5, 1919 - Friend of Robert Valentine, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Mabel Gillespie and Valentine, 1917-1991 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Data on Article by Robert Valentine and Albert Sidney Gregg (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Data on Belle Moskowitz (and Robert Valentine), 1916-1971 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - John Gorham Palfrey, Friend of Robert Valentine, 1913-1991 (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - Indians and Valentine also Polakoff, 1905-1921 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - R. Valentine, Protocalism, and Women Garment Workers 1913, 1924-1991 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Solomon Polakoff and Robert Valentine - 1991 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - Samuel Rosenthal - Rochester, NY, Died August 27, 1926 - NYC, Graduated Medical College U of PA - With R. Valentine When He Died 11/14/1916 (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - NY Times April 27, 1913 - "Industrial Psychologist to Prevent Labor Trouble" on Robert Valentine (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Robert Valentine Original Outline of His Work 2-8-1913 from Charlotte Taylor (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Robert Valentine and Felix Frankfurter Letters from Charlotte Taylor 1991, 1916-1991 (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Mary Fledderus, Data on International Industrial Relations Institute - 1925 Report and 1938 Data (Gives Background), 1925-1938 (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - 1929 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - 1930 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - 1931 International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 46)
  - 1932 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 47)
  - 1933 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 48)
  - 1934 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 49)
  - 1927 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 50)
  - 1928 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 51)
  - 1935 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 52)
  - 1936 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 53)
  - 1937 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 54)
  - 1938 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 55)
  - 1939 - International Industrial Relations Association (Box 29, Folder 56)
  - Mary Van Kleeck, Russell Sage Foundation Industrial Research Collection 1910-1950, Archives of Labor History and Union Affairs, Wayne State Univ. (Box 29, Folder 57)
  - Mary Van Kleek Papers on International Industrial Relations Institute, 1917-1929 (Box 29, Folder 58)
  - Various Kleeck Correspondence, 1928-1930 (Box 29, Folder 59)
  - MVK 1931 (Box 29, Folder 60)
  - MVK 1931 (Box 29, Folder 61)
  - MVK 1932-1933 (Box 29, Folder 62)
  - Van Kleeck - Fledderus, 1928-1934 (Box 29, Folder 63)
  - MVK 1933 (Box 29, Folder 64)
  - Van Kleeck - Fledderus Data, 1928-1983 (Box 29, Folder 65)
  - MVK 1934 (Box 29, Folder 66)
- A copy Mrs. Gilbreths dissertation with Taylor, Academy, and Gopsill material, used searching for Taylor in Philadelphia, in notebook form. Material on the group that ran Bureau of Personnel Administration courses in New York 1930-1931. Originals in (Box 30)
  - Research Phila. Directories 1864-1881 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Binder with copies of original documents
  - The American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Transactions, Vol. 28, The Art of Cutting Metals, 1906 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    Copies of original documents (in binder)
  - Edward Kimball Hall, 1912-1930 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Copies of Papers of the 1930-1931 Bureau of Personnel Administration (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Hoagland Dissertation, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 5)